Mayura Bandara Alahakoon

🕥 github.com/mayura-andrew 🥠 mayuraandrew.tech 🛅 linkedin.com/in/mayura-alahakoon

☑ mayuraalahakoon@gmail.com

Profile

I am a dedicated and curious Software Engineer with a profound enthusiasm for open-source technologies. My journey as an open-source enthusiast involves relentless exploration and experimentation with a diverse array of technologies and tools, all aimed at continuously enhancing my expertise.

Experience

Knowlihub | Founder

September 2023 - Present

Developing a community-driven open-source learning resource sharing platform that offers better online resources for learners, which are easily accessible and free of charge.

Esoft Metro College, Matale | Assistant Lab Administrator (Internship)

July 2022 – October 2022

Managed Computer Lab, Troubleshooted computers and network devices, Offered assistance to students with their programming projects, and provided technical guidance when needed.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering (Hons) - Reading

The Open University of Sri Lanka

September 2022 - Present

Pearson Higher National Diploma in Computing(Network Engineering)

Esoft Metro Campus

Result - Merit

Completed credits: 27/130

September 2021 - 2023

GCE Advanced Level in Technology Stream

Result - Pass

Government Science College, Matale

 $July\ 2019\ -\ March\ 2022$

PROJECTS

Knowlihub | JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML/CSS, Node.js, ReactJS, GoLang, Git/Github, Unix Shell, VS Code, MongoDB September 2023 - Present https://mayuraandrew.tech/projects

• Developing a community-driven free learning resources sharing platform.

CRUD/API Applications | JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML/CSS, Node.js, PHP, MySQL, C, VS Code, PostgreSQL, Firebase September 2021 – 2023 github.com/mayura-andrew

• Developed many CRUD operation applications and APIs.

PERSONAL AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, GoLang, Java, Python, JavaScript

Tools and Technologies: Git/GitHub, Linux, Node.js, VS Code, Containers, Cloud (GCP, AWS), Virtualization, CI/CD, ChatGPT, Google Bard, Perplexity, RESTAPI, MVC

Database Design and Management: SQL(MySQL, PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB)

Personal Skills: Passion for technology and for building something useful for people, Adaptability, Problem Solving, Continuous Learning, Research Aptitude.